Albert C. and Ralph D. Gilbert Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
Albert C. and Ralph D. Gilbert Papers.
undated, 1893-1896
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Gilbert, Albert C.
Gilbert, Ralph D.
.5 linear feet
The collection contains notes taken by brothers Albert C. Gilbert and Ralph D. Gilbert while attending Storrs Agricultural College. The notes cover Agriculture, Dairy and Veterinary classes between 1893 and 1896.
MSS19900058
Biography
Albert C. Gilbert attended Storrs Agricultural College between the years 1893 and 1897. After graduating in 1897, Albert Gilbert worked in the Storrs Experiment Station as an assistant to the Vice Director (1897-1898) and Assistant in Chemistry and Physics and Laboratory Assistant (1899-190?).
Ralph Davis Gilbert was born in Gilead, Connecticut, 10 June 1878. He entered Storrs Agricultural College in 1894 and graduated in 1897. Ralph attended the Massachusetts Agricultural College for a year (1900, B.S.) before entering Yale University, receiving his Ph.D. degree in 1904. During his professional career, Ralph Gilbert was employed at the Connecticut Experiment Station in New Haven, Connecticut, the laboratory of A.D. Little in Boston, Massachusetts, the Bowler Fertilizer Company and the Bowker Insecticide Company (later Bowker Chemical Company). Mr. Gilbert was involved with the development of the Bowker Company's principal product, Pryox, and the growth of the company as a leading manufacturer of insecticides and fungicides in the U.S. Mr. Ralph Gilbert died in 1919.
Scope and Content
The collection contains notes taken by Albert C. Gilbert and Ralph D. Gilbert while attending Storrs Agricultural College. The notes cover Agriculture, Dairy and Veterinary classes between 1893 and 1896.
Arrangement
Series I: Albert C. Gilbert ( undated ) contains three notebooks with notes on Agriculture and Dairying classes.
Series II: Ralph D. Gilbert ( undated, 1893-1896 ) contains eight notebooks with an emphasis on Veterinary classes.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, faculty, staff and students. See especially University Memorabilia Collection and other student collections. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Annual Report of the Trustees, Storrs Agricultural College (1898) Dodd Call No.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Gilbert, Albert C.; Gilbert, Ralph D.
Organizations:
Storrs Agricultural College.; University of Connecticut.
Places:
Storrs, Conn.
Subjects:
Document Types:
Notebooks.; Publications.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated in 1990.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Albert C. Gilbert, undated
  - Agriculture, undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Agriculture/Dairying, undated (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Dairying/Agriculture, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
- Series I: Ralph D. Gilbert, undated, 1893-1896
  - Agriculture, 1895 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Carbon Compounds, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Dairying, 1896 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Veterinary, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Veterinary, v. 1, 1894 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Veterinary, v. 2, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Veterinary, v. 3, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Veterinary Diseases, 1893 (Box 1:, Folder 11)